{
    "time": 30,
    "wordpress": [
        {
            "question": "1. WordPress is a ___?",
            "option1": "Content Management System",
            "option2": "Blogger",
            "option3": "Programming language",
            "option4": "All of these",
            "correctresponse": "Content Management System",
            "explanation": "WordPress is a content management system.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "2. CMS stands for ___?",
            "option1": "Content Management System",
            "option2": "Creator Management System",
            "option3": "Content Manager Source",
            "option4": "None of these",
            "correctresponse": "Content Management System",
            "explanation": "CMS stands for Content Management System.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "3. Which type of data can be stored in WordPress as media?",
            "option1": "Text",
            "option2": "Document",
            "option3": "Music",
            "option4": "All of these",
            "correctresponse": "All of these",
            "explanation": "WordPress can store all data such as text, photos, music, documents, etc.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "4. When was WordPress released?",
            "option1": "May 2003",
            "option2": "July 2003",
            "option3": "May 2001",
            "option4": "None of these",
            "correctresponse": "May 2003",
            "explanation": "WordPress was initially released on 27th May 2003 by Matt Mullenweg and Mike Little.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "5. Is WordPress free to use?",
            "option1": "Yes",
            "option2": "No",
            "option3": "it is very costly only elon musk can efford it",
            "option4": "Nothing is free",
            "correctresponse": "Yes",
            "explanation": "WordPress is an open-source platform and is free to use.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "6. Which of these is a feature of WordPress?",
            "option1": "User Management",
            "option2": "Provides tools for Search Engine Optimization",
            "option3": "Contains multiple themes to style our website",
            "option4": "All of these",
            "correctresponse": "All of these",
            "explanation": "Features of WordPress include managing multiple users, managing media files, library of multiple themes to style website, library of multiple plugins that provide functionalities, and allowing translation to multiple languages.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "7. Which of these is an advantage of WordPress?",
            "option1": "PHP requirement",
            "option2": "SEO tools make on-site SEO easier",
            "option3": "Frequent updates require multiple backup copies.",
            "option4": "All of these",
            "correctresponse": "SEO tools make on-site SEO easier",
            "explanation": "WordPress features SEO tools that make on-site SEO easier.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "8. Which of these is a free WordPress domain name provided to WordPress.com users?",
            "option1": "yoursite.WordPress.org",
            "option2": "Yoursite.org",
            "option3": "yousite.WordPress.com",
            "option4": "None of these",
            "correctresponse": "yousite.WordPress.com",
            "explanation": "WordPress.com provides a free website for free users under the subdomain of WordPress.com.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "9. Can you get a custom name using WordPress.com?",
            "option1": "Yes",
            "option2": "No",
            "option3": "i dont know",
            "option4": "i will not tell you",
            "correctresponse": "Yes",
            "explanation": "A custom domain name for a site can be claimed in WordPress for personal, premium, business plan users.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "10. Which WordPress type can be installed on a user's computer?",
            "option1": "WordPress.com",
            "option2": "WordPress.org",
            "option3": "Both",
            "option4": "None of these",
            "correctresponse": "WordPress.org",
            "explanation": "The WordPress.org type of WordPress can be downloaded and installed on your physical system.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "11. Which database is required by WordPress?",
            "option1": "MySQL",
            "option2": "MongoDB",
            "option3": "RDB",
            "option4": "None of these",
            "correctresponse": "MySQL",
            "explanation": "WordPress requires a MySQL database for its installation.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "12. Which of these fields is not required to be filled while first installing the WordPress?",
            "option1": "Site Title",
            "option2": "Username",
            "option3": "Post",
            "option4": "All of these",
            "correctresponse": "Post",
            "explanation": "The post of a WordPress blog is not needed at the time of installing WordPress. It can be added later on to the website.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "13. The Quick draft section in WordPress is used for ___?",
            "option1": "Creating mini-posts with titles and small details",
            "option2": "Editing posts",
            "option3": "Creating pages",
            "option4": "All of these",
            "correctresponse": "Creating mini-posts with titles and small details",
            "explanation": "The quick draft section in WordPress is used to create posts with only titles and basic points.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "14. Which of these is displayed using the WordPress news widget?",
            "option1": "Software version",
            "option2": "Software updates",
            "option3": "Alerts",
            "option4": "All of these",
            "correctresponse": "All of these",
            "explanation": "The new widget in WordPress displays the latest news from WordPress like the latest software version, updates, alerts, news, etc.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "15. Which of these is not seen on the WordPress dashboard?",
            "option1": "Site traffic",
            "option2": "Menu options",
            "option3": "Welcome text",
            "option4": "All of these",
            "correctresponse": "Site traffic",
            "explanation": "In the WordPress dashboard, there is no option/tab to see the site traffic.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "16. Which of these are general settings of WordPress?",
            "option1": "Site title",
            "option2": "Data format",
            "option3": "Time format",
            "option4": "All of these",
            "correctresponse": "All of these",
            "explanation": "The general settings page contains options such as site title, site tagline, updating site address, timezone, data format, time format, etc.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "17. Can writing settings be changed in WordPress?",
            "option1": "Yes",
            "option2": "No",
            "option3": "i dont know",
            "option4": "mute",
            "correctresponse": "Yes",
            "explanation": "WordPress consists of a setting option titled Writing Setting which allows its users to update writing settings for all the posts on the WordPress site.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "18. What is the default post Category for WordPress?",
            "option1": "The first category added on WordPress",
            "option2": "Uncategorized",
            "option3": "No category",
            "option4": "None of these",
            "correctresponse": "Uncategorized",
            "explanation": "The default post category for WordPress posts is uncategorized.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "19. What content of post can be displayed in the feed?",
            "option1": "Full post",
            "option2": "Summary of post",
            "option3": "Optional both A and B",
            "option4": "None of these",
            "correctresponse": "Optional both A and B",
            "explanation": "WordPress provides users an option to choose between the content of posts that can be displayed in the feeds. They are: Full post i.e. displaying all contents of the post, Summary of post. The default is full post but you can change it in the reading section.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "20. What task does search engine visibility performs in WordPress?",
            "option1": "Removes site visibility on Google",
            "option2": "Discourage search engines from indexing the site",
            "option3": "Both",
            "option4": "None of these",
            "correctresponse": "Removes site visibility on Google",
            "explanation": "The search engine visibility is a check on indexing of the site and when toggles off, it discourages search engines from indexing the site.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "21. What is the current version of WordPress (Feb 2022)?",
            "option1": "5.8.7",
            "option2": "5.9.1",
            "option3": "2",
            "option4": "None of these",
            "correctresponse": "5.9.1",
            "explanation": "As of February 2022, the most recent update of WordPress is 5.9.1.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "22. Can user-generated comments be moderated in WordPress?",
            "option1": "Yes",
            "option2": "No",
            "option3": "never",
            "option4": "i dont know",
            "correctresponse": "Yes",
            "explanation": "Comment moderation can be done in WordPress in the comments section to avoid spam comments on the blog.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "23. What are avatars in WordPress?",
            "option1": "A small image that is displayed beside the name of the user",
            "option2": "Name of creator",
            "option3": "A 3D graphic of a user in WordPress",
            "option4": "None of these",
            "correctresponse": "A small image that is displayed beside the name of the user",
            "explanation": "An avatar in WordPress is a small image that displays at the top-right-hand corner of the dashboard beside the name of the user.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "24. Where can you find permalink settings in WordPress?",
            "option1": "Setting -> Permalinks",
            "option2": "About -> Permalinks",
            "option3": "Tools -> Links -> Permalinks",
            "option4": "None of these",
            "correctresponse": "Setting -> Permalinks",
            "explanation": "Permalink settings can be changed by clicking settings and then clicking on permalinks.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "25. Which of these is an option to set permalink in WordPress?",
            "option1": "Updating using day and name",
            "option2": "Updating using month and name",
            "option3": "Updating using number",
            "option4": "All of these",
            "correctresponse": "All of these",
            "explanation": "WordPress provides the following options to update permalinks: Default, Day and name, Month and name, Post name, Number, Custom number.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "26. Can plugin files be edited in WordPress?",
            "option1": "Yes",
            "option2": "No",
            "option3": "very good",
            "option4": "i am leaving",
            "correctresponse": "Yes",
            "explanation": "Plugin files can be edited in WordPress.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "27. plugins in WordPress are used to ___?",
            "option1": "Easily modify, customize or enhance WordPress sites",
            "option2": "Change UI of the dashboard",
            "option3": "Add a new address to the website",
            "option4": "All of these",
            "correctresponse": "Easily modify, customize or enhance WordPress sites",
            "explanation": "WordPress plugins are used to easily modify, customize or enhance WordPress sites.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "28. All plugins installed on WordPress can be viewed at?",
            "option1": "plugins -> add plugin",
            "option2": "settings -> plugin",
            "option3": "plugins -> installed plugin",
            "option4": "None of these",
            "correctresponse": "plugins -> installed plugin",
            "explanation": "All the installed plugins on WordPress can be viewed at: plugins -> installed plugin.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "29. Is it required to activate the plugin after installing it?",
            "option1": "Yes",
            "option2": "No",
            "option3": "yes and no",
            "option4": "where am i",
            "correctresponse": "Yes",
            "explanation": "For working, the plugin is required to be activated after installation.",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "30. Plugin update is used to ___?",
            "option1": "Update some parts of plugins code based on the requirement.",
            "option2": "Install an updated version",
            "option3": "Add a new file to the plugin",
            "option4": "All of these",
            "correctresponse": "Install",
            "explanation": "Plugin update is used to Install an updated version",
            "time": 1
        }
    ]
}